<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Mana Theory on Mana Theory</title><link>https://manatheory.com/</link><description>Recent content in The Mana Theory on Mana Theory</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manatheory.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Mana Theory Comic</title><link>https://manatheory.com/comics/the-theory/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://manatheory.com/comics/the-theory/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Theory</title><link>https://manatheory.com/full/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://manatheory.com/full/</guid><description>In many role-playing games, there is a concept of a Mana bar. This bar holds “Mana&amp;quot; — a magical reserve of power that you can use or spend on performing actions, activities, and tasks. At full mana, the character can do pretty much anything without fear of running out. There are buffs that you can apply to boost or increase your mana, debuffs that will decrease or stunt your mana, and mana regenerates when the character is at rest (sleeping or out of combat).</description></item><item><title>The Motivation Behind the Theory</title><link>https://manatheory.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://manatheory.com/about/</guid><description>When The Mana Theory first came about, I had no idea that was autistic or that I had ADHD. All I knew is that I struggled with some form of anxiety and depression that affected my daily life and my ability to handle life and do chores.
Sometimes I could readily articulate exactly what the issue was and why I was operating below what had become expected: my Grandfather passed away, my job was particularly draining this week, this specific event was stressing me out, etc.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Game Terminology</title><link>https://manatheory.com/terminology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://manatheory.com/terminology/</guid><description>If you’re unfamiliar with gaming terminology, this is a great place to start. The reason this analogy works so well is because there are explicit parallels that can be drawn between Mental Health and gaming mechanics.
Even at the most basic level, games, especially role playing games (RPGs), have a real-to-life component to them. In role playing games, you create a character and then play as that character. This assumption of character puts you into the context and mindset of that character, and so when we draw parallels between the character and you, we can say that what happens to your character in game, is like what happens to you in real life.</description></item></channel></rss>